RG 004:113, Portland Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Portland Probate Court records
1802-2001, bulk 1824-1975
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Portland District)
32.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1914-1933; Probate files, 1802-1996, bulk 1824-1975; Wills, 1824-2001, bulk 1824-1974.
RG004_113
2011-017, 2012-037, 2012-038
Historical Note
Portland, Middlesex County, Town established in May 1841, Parent Town: Chatham (East Hampton)
The Portland Probate District was constituted April 22, 1913, from the Chatham Probate District. The Chatham (East Hampton) Probate District Court records previous to January 6, 1915 are held by the Portland Probate District. The Portland Probate District merged with the East Haddam, East Hampton, and Marlborough Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #14 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Haddam, East Hampton, Marlborough and Portland.
Town of Portland, Probate District chronology:
May 1841 - April 21, 1913, Chatham (i.e. East Hampton) District (records included with those of the Portland Probate District)
April 22, 1913 - January 4, 2011, Portland District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 14 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 25-26, 1914-1933. These record books continue the sequence of numbering of the Chatham (East Hampton) Probate District that held court in Portland prior to the creation of the Portland District. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 26.
Probate files, 1802-1996, bulk 1824-1975. Includes files from the Chatham (East Hampton) Probate District previous to January 6, 1915. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Wills, 1824-2001, bulk 1824-1974.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 25 and 26.
Probate files in accession 2012-037 and wills in accession 2012-038 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2012-037.
Wills: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the wills in accession 2012-038.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Hampton; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Portland
Places:
East Hampton (Conn.); Portland (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Probate files dated 1921 or later are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2012-037, Probate files, 1802-1996, bulk 1824-1975, and Accessopm 2012-038, Wills, 1824-2001, bulk 1824-1974, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2011-017 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 30, 2011.
The probate files in accession 2012-037 and wills in accession 2012-038 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on May 8, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1914-1933; 1.5 cubic feet (2 volumes); 2012-015
  - Records, 1914-1922 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1918-1933 (Volume 26)
- Probate files, 1802-1996, bulk 1924-1975; 29 cubic feet; 2012-037
  - Anononson - Axelson (Box 1)
  - Babcock - Bengston (Box 2)
  - Bennett - Brooks (Box 3)
  - Brown - Cavanaugh (Box 4)
  - Chagnot - Congdove (Box 5)
  - Conklin - Csere (Box 6)
  - Cuichta - Dmuchowski (Box 7)
  - Doan - Ewing (Box 8)
  - Fairman - Giddings (Box 9)
  - Gildersleeve (Box 10)
  - Geary - Gustafson (Box 11)
  - Hagelberg - Hall (Box 12)
  - Halliday - Hyman (Box 13)
  - Iner - Kellogg (Box 14)
  - Kelly - Leary (Box 15)
  - Lechtweis - Markkham (Box 16)
  - Marks - Mitchelson (Box 17)
  - Moard - Nyman (Box 18)
  - Oakliff - Pascall (Box 19)
  - Pasquarelli - Piatti (Box 20)
  - Pickering - Raftery (Box 21)
  - Rainey - Rozwoda (Box 22)
  - Ruffin - Schelberg (Box 23)
  - Shephard - Stetson (Box 24)
  - Stevens - Sullivan (Box 25)
  - Sulomicz - Tyrsick (Box 26)
  - Uehir - West (Box 27)
  - Westergon - Worthington (Box 28)
  - Wright - Zuerlein (Box 29)
- Wills, 1824-2001, bulk 1824-1974; 2 cubic feet; 2012-038
  - A - L (Box 1)
  - M - Z (Box 2)